<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage on Erwin Kuhn</title>
    <link>https://erwinkn.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepage on Erwin Kuhn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://erwinkn.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting conflict-free replicated data types to production</title>
      <link>https://erwinkn.com/getting-crdts-to-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erwinkn.com/getting-crdts-to-production/</guid>
      <description>Hi! This is the introduction to a series of working notes on the missing pieces before we can start building offline collaborative apps using replicated data types (RDTs or CRDTs if they are conflict-free).
So far, the plan is:
 Introduction: The road to offline collaborative apps (you are here) Conflict-free replicated databases (CRDBs): design Conflict-free replicated databases (CRDBs): implementation Decentralized data migrations Real-world CRDTs: Topogether, an app for outdoor climbing and collaborative cartography Extensible CRDTs: building new data structures and invariants in user-land Secure CRDTs: access control and Byzantine fault tolerance Optimizing CRDTs: make it fast, make it small  This series will take a while, as I will be building an experimental RDT library from scratch and putting it into production on Topogether.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything is an incremental computation</title>
      <link>https://erwinkn.com/incremental/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erwinkn.com/incremental/</guid>
      <description>There are some algorithms in computer science that just keep coming up everywhere. There&amp;rsquo;s one that I see everywhere I look, but never heard described as universal: the algorithm behind incremental computation, reactivity, or change propagation - however you want to call it.
Its most famous implementation is the one that powers spreadsheets like Excel. If you have a large sheet with many formulas and the value of one cell changes, how do you propagate that change in the most efficient manner?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s no plan B for concrete</title>
      <link>https://erwinkn.com/concrete/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erwinkn.com/concrete/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Welcome to the first article in a 3-part series about the cement &amp;amp; concrete industries and their place in the climate fight. It provides a general introduction to the subject, with some surprising facts I discovered along the way.
This is a personal perspective and is subject to change based on feedback and further discussions. Feel free to reach out!
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working for the past year with  Vicat, (sidenote:  For the anecdote, Louis Vicat is the inventor of one of the first modern cement formulations in 1817!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://erwinkn.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erwinkn.com/about/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR   I&#39;m incredibly passionate about climate, computer science, food &amp; wine, climbing, technology and science fiction. Pick any topic in there and I&#39;m happy to talk hours about it.  I&#39;ve worked on data markets and blockchains, been a food photographer and am now focusing on writing code for the climate.  You can reach me at erwin.kuhn@protonmail.com  Things I&#39;ve done   I&#39;m a software builder by vocation, but being of the generalist type, I&#39;ve dabbled in a variety of different areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://erwinkn.com/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erwinkn.com/now/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working with Vicat on how to get to net-zero emissions in the cement industry. With them, I&amp;rsquo;m building N-Zero, a modelling tool to create long term roadmaps towards net-zero CO2 emissions. While the project is private, I wrote a primer on the cement &amp;amp; concrete industries from a climate lens here.
I recently caught the deep learning bug as well. Right now, I&amp;rsquo;m working on mini-dl, an educational deep learning framework built on top of JAX, and simple-grad, an introduction going from zero to a complete auto-differentiation system, similar to what PyTorch or JAX use under the hood.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
