<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homepage on Erwin Kuhn</title><link>https://erwinkn.com/</link><description>Recent content in Homepage on Erwin Kuhn</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://erwinkn.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Transfering state from server to client with Blazor WASM and prerendering</title><link>https://erwinkn.com/tricks/blazor-rehydration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erwinkn.com/tricks/blazor-rehydration/</guid><description>I wanted to brush up my Blazor skills. I had been using the new .NET framework (sidenote: I&amp;rsquo;ll give an introduction to Blazor and the whole experience of putting it into production in a separate blog post. ) in my work with Vicat, an international cement &amp;amp; concrete group based in France, to develop a modelling tool for long term roadmaps towards carbon neutrality. Coding with it was a joy, but I had doubts about its overall performance.</description></item><item><title>A primer on cement &amp; concrete from the climate lens</title><link>https://erwinkn.com/blog/cement/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erwinkn.com/blog/cement/</guid><description>WIP: this article is not yet complete. I am still gathering feedback and information to finalize this guide. If you arrived here, I would be very happy to hear about your thoughts on the article.
This is the first post in a series about the cement &amp;amp; concrete industries and their place in the climate fight. It provides a general introduction to the subject, with some surprising facts I discovered along the way.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://erwinkn.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erwinkn.com/about/</guid><description>TL;DR I'm incredibly passionate about climate, computer science, food &amp; wine, climbing, technology and science fiction. Pick any topic in there and I'm happy to talk hours about it. I've worked on data markets and blockchains, been a food photographer and am now focusing on writing code for the climate. You can reach me at erwin.kuhn@protonmail.com Things I've done I'm a software builder by vocation, but being of the generalist type, I've dabbled in a variety of different areas.</description></item><item><title>Now</title><link>https://erwinkn.com/now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erwinkn.com/now/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working with Vicat on how to get to net-zero emissions in the cement industry. With them, I&amp;rsquo;m building N-Zero, a modelling tool to create long term roadmaps towards net-zero CO2 emissions. While the project is private, I wrote a primer on the cement &amp;amp; concrete industries from a climate lens here.
I recently caught the deep learning bug as well. Right now, I&amp;rsquo;m working on mini-dl, an educational deep learning framework built on top of JAX, and simple-grad, an introduction going from zero to a complete auto-differentiation system, similar to what PyTorch or JAX use under the hood.</description></item></channel></rss>